<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1 | TESLa@CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication-type/1/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/publication-type/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>1</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://teslacu.org/images/icon_hu60bb029947ff14bd97c2fafb98779c9f_124002_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>1</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication-type/1/</link></image><item><title>Identifying Complex Dynamics of Interacting Turbulent Jets through Modal Decompositions</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_int_jets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_int_jets/</guid><description>&lt;p>ABSTRACT&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turbulence Model Development Using Markov Chain Monte Carlo Approximate Bayesian Computation</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_abc_rans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_abc_rans/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Autonomic Closure for Turbulent Flows Using Approximate Bayesian Computation</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2018_autonomic_abc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2018_autonomic_abc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lagrangian Analysis of Vorticity Dynamics in Turbulent Premixed Flames</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2017_fpta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2017_fpta/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evaluation of Reduced-Order Models for Predictions of Separated and Vortical Flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2016_rom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2016_rom/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effect of Flame Spacing and Flow Velocity on the Dynamics of Three Interacting V-Flames</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/effect-of-flame-spacing-and-flow-velocity-on-the-dynamics-of-three-interacting-v-flames/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/effect-of-flame-spacing-and-flow-velocity-on-the-dynamics-of-three-interacting-v-flames/</guid><description>&lt;p>Flame interaction is a phenomenon that occurs in a number of combustion devices and can change both the time-averaged shape and dynamical behavior of flames. In this study, we investigate the impact of flame spacing and bulk flow velocity on the time averaged characteristics of three, two-dimensional, bluff-body stabilized V-flames. Velocity fields and flame edges are extracted from particle image velocimetry (PIV) data to quantify the differences in behavior of these flames at three flame spacings and two bulk flow velocities with Reynolds numbers of 4000 and 8000 based on bluff-body diameter. Higher bulk flow velocities cause the flame intersection point to move downstream. Increasing the bluff-body spacing also moves the intersection point farther
downstream. Reducing bluff-body spacing causes the recirculation zone behind the bluff bodies to significantly diminish and reduces flame brush growth. Discussion of the impact of these geometric and flow parameters is discussed and plans for future work are provided.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>