<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Olga Doronina | TESLa@CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/olga-doronina/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/author/olga-doronina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Olga Doronina</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://teslacu.org/author/olga-doronina/avatar_huba3fdfcdf06e8a6d45e7ebabe76ba20d_2232883_270x270_fill_q90_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Olga Doronina</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/olga-doronina/</link></image><item><title>Turbulence Model Development Using Markov Chain Monte Carlo Approximate Bayesian Computation</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_abc_rans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2019_abc_rans/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simulating Aerodynamics of a Moving Body Specified by Immersed Boundaries on Dynamically Adaptive Unstructured Meshes</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper is devoted to the development of integrated technology for numerical simulation of aerodynamics of moving bodies prescribed by the immersed boundaries method on unstructured meshes. The dynamic mesh adaptation is used to improve the accuracy. The mesh adaptation method in use is built on the base of nodes-redistribution techniques. Its implementation implies the solution of additional differential equation governing the mesh movement. The method allows to keep a topology of the initial mesh and does not increase significantly the computational costs. The technology is developed for 2D formulations and verified on model problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autonomic Closure for Turbulent Flows Using Approximate Bayesian Computation</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/2018_autonomic_abc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/2018_autonomic_abc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Numerical study of acoustic radiation dynamics of a Rankine vortex</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper continues investigations of a fundamental problem important for understanding the nature of vortex flows: sound radiation by a perturbed Rankine vortex. Results of numerical simulation are presented for both quadrupole and higher-mode radiations. The structure and dynamics of tonal acoustic radiation generated by a vortex are considered in detail. The transition of a Rankine vortex to a perturbed state under small external perturbation is considered. Calculations are performed using the EBR scheme implemented by NOISEtte software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Numerical simulation of acoustic waves scattering by isolated vortex structures</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem of sound scattering by an isolated vortex is of interest in itself and the basis for understanding the interaction between acoustic waves and a vortex flow, including the process of sound generation by turbulence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to solve this problem we use the linearized Euler equations in the nonuniform average field, taking into account isoentropic medium. For numerical simulation, we also use a scheme based on the quasi-one-dimensional reconstruction of the 5th order of accuracy. Calculations are performed using the parallel research code NOISEtte (KIAM RAS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We give the calculational results of the plane acoustic wave scattering by isoentropic Gaussian-core vortex of a constant velocity circulation and demonstrate the convergence of solutions to the benchmark solution. Unlike the other authors results, not only Cartesian meshes, but quasi-uniform unstructured triangular meshes are also used. It is found that in both cases the results are almost the identical for the same number of nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Further, we consider the problem of the cylindrical point source acoustic wave scattering by the Rankine vortex. We carry out the calculations on unstructured meshes and compare the results of different approaches to the problem: a finite-volume approach (NOISEtte), a finite element approach (Actran DGM) and a finite-difference Cabaret scheme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, the results confirm that the software system NOISEtte and the used method can be successfully applied to the numerical simulation of interaction between acoustic waves and vortex structures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turbulence modeling</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="turbulence-model-development-using-approximate-bayesian-computation">Turbulence model development using Approximate Bayesian Computation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Real-world turbulent flows are challenging to simulate due to the high computational cost of resolving all their relevant spatial and temporal scales. There are two common approaches to reduce the cost of such simulations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Large_eddy_simulation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Large-Eddy Simulations (LES)&lt;/a>, which directly resolve turbulence on large scales and use subgrid-scale (SGS) models to represent small-scale physics&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reynolds-averaged_Navier%E2%80%93Stokes_equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reynolds averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS)&lt;/a> approaches, which resolve only averaged quantities and model turbulent fluctuations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, there is no universally accurate turbulence model in either of these approaches. Besides that, all models rely on empirical coefficients that we must calibrate for different flows and geometries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We suggest using the
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approximate_Bayesian_computation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC)&lt;/a> methods, also known as likelihood-free methods. ABC is a data-driven approach, which uses experimental or higher fidelity data to approximate the probability distribution of model parameters. As a result, we can choose model parameters and quantify their uncertainty based on (or even sample from) this estimated probability distribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ABC is based on the Bayesian approach but does not require knowing the analytical expression for a likelihood function. The primary advantages of ABC are its lower cost relative to full Bayesian methods and its flexibility in parameter estimation for complex models, e.g., turbulence models, which consist of partial differential equations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We created a framework called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/olgadoronina/ABC_MCMC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TurbABC&lt;/a> for turbulent model parameters estimation. TurbABC combines ABC with Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling, an adaptive proposal, and calibration steps to accelerate the parameter estimation process. We demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of TurbABC by estimating parameters of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonlinear SGS closures using reference data from direct numerical simulations of homogeneous isotropic turbulence&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonequilibrium anisotropy RANS closure in homogeneous turbulent flow with rapidly changing strain tensor&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>RANS model parameters estimation in inhomogeneous turbulent flow (axisymmetric transonic bump)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>