<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2 | TESLa@CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication-type/2/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>2</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://teslacu.org/images/icon_hu60bb029947ff14bd97c2fafb98779c9f_124002_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>2</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication-type/2/</link></image><item><title>Scaling of the puffing Strouhal number for buoyant jets and plumes</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/wimer-scaling-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/wimer-scaling-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Characterization of the Buoyant Jet above a Catalytic Combustor Using Wavelength Modulation Spectroscopy</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-characterization-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-characterization-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Detonation initiation by compressible turbulence thermodynamic fluctuations</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-detonation-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-detonation-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wake steering optimization under uncertainty</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/quick-wake-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/quick-wake-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>WENO interpolation for Lagrangian particles in highly compressible flow regimes</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/kozak-weno-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/kozak-weno-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Efficient simulation of turbulent diffusion flames in OpenFOAM using adaptive mesh refinement</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/lapointe-efficient-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/lapointe-efficient-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OH radical measurements in combustion environments using wavelength modulation spectroscopy and dual-frequency comb spectroscopy near 1491 nm</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-oh-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-oh-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of isothermal stratification strength on vorticity dynamics for single-mode compressible Rayleigh-Taylor instability</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/wieland-effects-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/wieland-effects-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reduced Gas-Phase Kinetic Models for Burning of Douglas Fir</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/glusman-reduced-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/glusman-reduced-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Characterization of OH, H2O, and temperature profiles in industrial flame treatment systems interacting with polymer films</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-characterization-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hayden-characterization-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scaling and collapse of conditional velocity structure functions in turbulent premixed flames</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/whitman-scaling-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/whitman-scaling-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simulating Aerodynamics of a Moving Body Specified by Immersed Boundaries on Dynamically Adaptive Unstructured Meshes</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper is devoted to the development of integrated technology for numerical simulation of aerodynamics of moving bodies prescribed by the immersed boundaries method on unstructured meshes. The dynamic mesh adaptation is used to improve the accuracy. The mesh adaptation method in use is built on the base of nodes-redistribution techniques. Its implementation implies the solution of additional differential equation governing the mesh movement. The method allows to keep a topology of the initial mesh and does not increase significantly the computational costs. The technology is developed for 2D formulations and verified on model problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effects of Langmuir Turbulence on Upper Ocean Carbonate Chemistry</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/smith-effects-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/smith-effects-2018/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Parameter estimation for complex thermal-fluid flows using approximate Bayesian computation</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/christopher-parameter-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/christopher-parameter-2018/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spatially localized multi-scale energy transfer in turbulent premixed combustion</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/kim-spatially-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/kim-spatially-2018/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Flow dynamics in a variable-spacing, three bluff-body flowfield</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/flow-dynamics-in-a-variable-spacing-three-bluff-body-flowfield/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/flow-dynamics-in-a-variable-spacing-three-bluff-body-flowfield/</guid><description>&lt;p>This work explores the wake dynamics of systems with three bluff bodies with variable spacing. Studies of single-wake systems have shown that coherent wake vortices have a regular and predictable periodicity. A growing literature of dual-wake studies has shown that multi-wake systems are more stochastic than single-wake systems, and their dynamics are highly dependent on the spacing between the wakes. Here, we expand on this literature by investigating three-wake systems and find that the coherent dynamics of the wakes are highly intermittent. We use proper orthogonal decomposition to extract the most energetic modes of the three-wake system at six bluff-body spacings that span a range of dynamical “regimes.” After describing the time-dependent behavior of the interacting wakes in these regimes, we use a statistical approach to describe the relative phase between oscillations in each of the wakes, identifying regimes where oscillations are more or less random. Interestingly, the wake oscillations are less random when the bluff bodies are positioned very close and relatively far from each other. In between these two extremes, an intermediary regime is identified where the wake oscillations are almost completely random; this finding parallels data from the dual-wake literature. Finally, we discuss the implications of the observed behaviors and possible future directions for this work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lagrangian analysis of high-speed turbulent premixed reacting flows: Thermochemical trajectories in hydrogen–air flames</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-lagrangian-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-lagrangian-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Canard–wing interference effects on the flight characteristics of a transonic passenger aircraft</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/ghoreyshi-canardwing-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/ghoreyshi-canardwing-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of climate oscillations on wildland fire potential in the continental United States: Climate Effects on Fire Potential</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/mason-effects-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/mason-effects-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Experimental Development and Computational Optimization of Flat Heat Pipes for CubeSat Applications</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/isaacs-experimental-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/isaacs-experimental-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Optimization of wind plant layouts using an adjoint approach</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/king-optimization-2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/king-optimization-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lagrangian analysis of premixed autoignition in compressible turbulence</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-lagrangian-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-lagrangian-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The cross-scale physical-space transfer of kinetic energy in turbulent premixed flames</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/obrien-cross-scale-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/obrien-cross-scale-2017/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Numerical study of acoustic radiation dynamics of a Rankine vortex</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper investigates a problem of sound radiation by a perturbed Rankine vortex, which is important for understanding the nature of vortex flows. We present numerical simulation results for quadrupole and higher mode radiations and consider the structure and dynamics of tonal acoustic radiation generated by a vortex in detail. We also describe the transition of a Rankine vortex to a perturbed state under small external perturbation. Numerical simulations are performed using the EBR (Edge-based reconstruction) scheme implemented in NOISEtte.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spectral kinetic energy transfer in turbulent premixed reacting flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-spectral-2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/towery-spectral-2016/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Surface waves affect frontogenesis</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/suzuki-surface-2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/suzuki-surface-2016/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Autonomic closure for turbulence simulations</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/king-autonomic-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/king-autonomic-2016/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of submesoscale turbulence on ocean tracers</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/smith-effects-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/smith-effects-2016/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Experimental Development and Computational Optimization of Flat Heat Pipes for CubeSat Applications</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/isaacs-experimental-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/isaacs-experimental-2016/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analysis of turbulent bending moments in tidal current boundary layers</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/alexander-analysis-2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/alexander-analysis-2015/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Characterization of turbulence anisotropy, coherence, and intermittency at a prospective tidal energy site: Observational data analysis</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/mccaffrey-characterization-2015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/mccaffrey-characterization-2015/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of climate oscillations on wind resource variability in the United States</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-effects-2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-effects-2015/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Langmuir–Submesoscale Interactions: Descriptive Analysis of Multiscale Frontal Spindown Simulations</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-langmuirsubmesoscale-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-langmuirsubmesoscale-2014/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modeling of Non-Equilibrium Homogeneous Turbulence in Rapidly Compressed Flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-modeling-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-modeling-2014/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Numerical simulation of acoustic waves scattering by isolated vortex structures</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem of sound scattering by an isolated vortex is not only interesting by itself but also is fundamental for understanding the interaction between acoustic waves and vortex flow, including the process of sound generation by turbulence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When turbulence is represented by a distribution of localized vortices with certain static properties, the acoustic field scattered by such flow is a superposition of scattered acoustic fields from each vortex. Therefore, the description of an elementary event, scattering of sound by an isolated vortex, can be used to predict the impact on the acoustic field of the turbulent flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the numerical simulation of this problem, we use a linear approximation of the mathematical model. This approximation is quite realistic because it reveals the main properties of the studied phenomena. Thus we model the problem using a system of linearized Euler equations, in which a vortex is defined as a background field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We use EBR (Edge-Based Reconstruction) numerical scheme, the 5th order scheme based on the quasi-one-dimensional reconstruction, implemented in highly parallel research code NOISEtte (KIAM RAS). One of the goals of this study is to test the EBR scheme&amp;rsquo;s ability to model such problems on unstructured grids and to assess its accuracy and efficiency compared to other approaches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we show the simulation results of the plane acoustic wave scattering by isentropic Gaussian-core vortex with a constant circulation velocity and demonstrate the grid convergence to the benchmark solution. Besides Cartesian meshes, we also use quasi-uniform unstructured triangular meshes and demonstrate that the results are almost identical for the same number of mesh points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also consider the problem of the cylindrical point source acoustic wave scattering by the Rankine vortex. We perform simulations on unstructured meshes and compare the results of different numerical approaches: a finite-volume approach (NOISEtte EBR), a finite element approach (Actran DGM), and a finite-difference (Cabaret scheme).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The results confirm that NOISEtte and this numerical method can be successfully used to simulate the interaction between acoustic waves and vortex structures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intermittency in premixed turbulent reacting flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-intermittency-2012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-intermittency-2012/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Local dissipation scales and energy dissipation-rate moments in channel flow</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-local-2012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-local-2012/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The form and orientation of Langmuir cells for misaligned winds and waves</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/van-roekel-form-2012/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/van-roekel-form-2012/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Statistics of the energy dissipation rate and local enstrophy in turbulent channel flow</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-statistics-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-statistics-2012/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interactions between turbulence and flames in premixed reacting flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-interactions-2011/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-interactions-2011/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nonlocal form of the rapid pressure-strain correlation in turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-nonlocal-2009/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-nonlocal-2009/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Frequency response of periodically sheared homogeneous turbulence</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-frequency-2009/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-frequency-2009/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Direct assessment of vorticity alignment with local and nonlocal strain rates in turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-direct-2008/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-direct-2008/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reynolds stress closure for nonequilibrium effects in turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-reynolds-2008/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-reynolds-2008/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Local and nonlocal strain rate fields and vorticity alignment in turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-local-2008/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/publication/hamlington-local-2008/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>