<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | TESLa@CU</title>
    <link>tesla-cu.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="tesla-cu.github.io/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/tesla-cu.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>tesla-cu.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Aerodynamics of a Moving Body Specified by Immersed Boundaries on Dynamically Adaptive Unstructured Meshes</title>
      <link>tesla-cu.github.io/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>tesla-cu.github.io/author/simulating-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-specified-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptive-unstructured-meshes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper is devoted to the development of integrated technology for numerical simulation of aerodynamics of moving bodies prescribed by the immersed boundaries method on unstructured meshes. The dynamic mesh adaptation is used to improve the accuracy. The mesh adaptation method in use is built on the base of nodes-redistribution techniques. Its implementation implies the solution of additional differential equation governing the mesh movement. The method allows to keep a topology of the initial mesh and does not increase significantly the computational costs. The technology is developed for 2D formulations and verified on model problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow dynamics in a variable-spacing, three bluff-body flowfield</title>
      <link>tesla-cu.github.io/author/flow-dynamics-in-a-variable-spacing-three-bluff-body-flowfield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>tesla-cu.github.io/author/flow-dynamics-in-a-variable-spacing-three-bluff-body-flowfield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work explores the wake dynamics of systems with three bluff bodies with variable spacing. Studies of single-wake systems have shown that coherent wake vortices have a regular and predictable periodicity. A growing literature of dual-wake studies has shown that multi-wake systems are more stochastic than single-wake systems, and their dynamics are highly dependent on the spacing between the wakes. Here, we expand on this literature by investigating three-wake systems and find that the coherent dynamics of the wakes are highly intermittent. We use proper orthogonal decomposition to extract the most energetic modes of the three-wake system at six bluff-body spacings that span a range of dynamical “regimes.” After describing the time-dependent behavior of the interacting wakes in these regimes, we use a statistical approach to describe the relative phase between oscillations in each of the wakes, identifying regimes where oscillations are more or less random. Interestingly, the wake oscillations are less random when the bluff bodies are positioned very close and relatively far from each other. In between these two extremes, an intermediary regime is identified where the wake oscillations are almost completely random; this finding parallels data from the dual-wake literature. Finally, we discuss the implications of the observed behaviors and possible future directions for this work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical study of acoustic radiation dynamics of a Rankine vortex</title>
      <link>tesla-cu.github.io/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>tesla-cu.github.io/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper continues investigations of a fundamental problem important for understanding the nature of vortex flows: sound radiation by a perturbed Rankine vortex. Results of numerical simulation are presented for both quadrupole and higher-mode radiations. The structure and dynamics of tonal acoustic radiation generated by a vortex are considered in detail. The transition of a Rankine vortex to a perturbed state under small external perturbation is considered. Calculations are performed using the EBR scheme implemented by NOISEtte software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulation of acoustic waves scattering by isolated vortex structures</title>
      <link>tesla-cu.github.io/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>tesla-cu.github.io/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem of sound scattering by an isolated vortex  is of interest in itself and the basis for understanding the interaction between acoustic waves and a vortex flow, including the process of sound generation by turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to solve this problem we use the linearized Euler equations in the nonuniform average field, taking into account isoentropic medium. For numerical simulation, we also use a scheme based on the quasi-one-dimensional reconstruction of the 5th order of accuracy. Calculations are performed using the parallel research code NOISEtte (KIAM RAS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give the calculational results of the plane acoustic wave scattering by isoentropic Gaussian-core vortex of a constant velocity circulation and demonstrate the convergence of solutions to the benchmark solution. Unlike the other authors  results, not only Cartesian meshes, but quasi-uniform unstructured triangular meshes are also used. It is found that in both cases the results are almost the identical for the same number of nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, we consider the problem of the cylindrical point source acoustic wave scattering by the Rankine vortex. We carry out the calculations on unstructured meshes and compare the results of different approaches to the problem: a finite-volume approach (NOISEtte), a finite element approach (Actran DGM) and a finite-difference Cabaret scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the results confirm that the software system NOISEtte and the used method can be successfully applied to the numerical simulation of interaction between acoustic waves and vortex structures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
