<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>N. S. Zdanova | TESLa | CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/n.-s.-zdanova/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/author/n.-s.-zdanova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>N. S. Zdanova</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://teslacu.org/images/logo_hu135bca77aa614af613f5ab7a46762921_9259_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>N. S. Zdanova</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/n.-s.-zdanova/</link></image><item><title>Numerical simulation of acoustic waves scattering by isolated vortex structures</title><link>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem of sound scattering by an isolated vortex is not only interesting by itself but also is fundamental for understanding the interaction between acoustic waves and vortex flow, including the process of sound generation by turbulence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When turbulence is represented by a distribution of localized vortices with certain static properties, the acoustic field scattered by such flow is a superposition of scattered acoustic fields from each vortex. Therefore, the description of an elementary event, scattering of sound by an isolated vortex, can be used to predict the impact on the acoustic field of the turbulent flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the numerical simulation of this problem, we use a linear approximation of the mathematical model. This approximation is quite realistic because it reveals the main properties of the studied phenomena. Thus we model the problem using a system of linearized Euler equations, in which a vortex is defined as a background field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We use EBR (Edge-Based Reconstruction) numerical scheme, the 5th order scheme based on the quasi-one-dimensional reconstruction, implemented in highly parallel research code NOISEtte (KIAM RAS). One of the goals of this study is to test the EBR scheme&amp;rsquo;s ability to model such problems on unstructured grids and to assess its accuracy and efficiency compared to other approaches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we show the simulation results of the plane acoustic wave scattering by isentropic Gaussian-core vortex with a constant circulation velocity and demonstrate the grid convergence to the benchmark solution. Besides Cartesian meshes, we also use quasi-uniform unstructured triangular meshes and demonstrate that the results are almost identical for the same number of mesh points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also consider the problem of the cylindrical point source acoustic wave scattering by the Rankine vortex. We perform simulations on unstructured meshes and compare the results of different numerical approaches: a finite-volume approach (NOISEtte EBR), a finite element approach (Actran DGM), and a finite-difference (Cabaret scheme).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The results confirm that NOISEtte and this numerical method can be successfully used to simulate the interaction between acoustic waves and vortex structures.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>