<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Turbulence | TESLa@CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/tag/turbulence/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/tag/turbulence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Turbulence</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><image><url>https://teslacu.org/images/icon_hu60bb029947ff14bd97c2fafb98779c9f_124002_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Turbulence</title><link>https://teslacu.org/tag/turbulence/</link></image><item><title>Fire dynamics</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/wildland_fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/wildland_fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Novel computational techniques are required to offset the cost of high-fidelity simulations of fire in both built and natural environments. Such fires are nearly always distinguished by wide ranges of spatiotemporal scales and physical phenomena, thus placing considerable constraints on the achievable size and complexity of simulations. We have made new progress in using a well-known technique – Adaptive Mesh Refinement (AMR) – to overcome these limitations. With AMR, grid cells are placed only where they are needed to resolve large gradients in velocity, temperature, species, and other user-defined flow quantities. We demonstrate the use of an AMR-enabled FireFOAM solver for simulations of pool fires, and compare simulation results with experimental data and prior computational efforts. Capabilities of the new solver are outlined, with a view towards providing this tool, once completed, to the broader fire modeling community. We also highlight the potential of AMR to enable future direct numerical simulations (DNS) of fire dynamics, in particular using the multi-physics code PeleLM. Such simulations will provide some of the highest-fidelity predictions of fire dynamics to date, and will be made possible through the use of AMR to minimize the computational cost that typically accompanies DNS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-speed combustion</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulent_combustion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulent_combustion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since 2014, we have undertaken extensive studies of the multi-scale interactions between turbulence and premixed flames, particularly focused on highly turbulent conditions. Using a conditional Fourier analysis and data from direct numerical simulations (DNS) of premixed flames, we provided the first quantitative evidence of net kinetic energy backscatter in turbulent premixed combustion. In particular, an analysis of spectral kinetic energy transfer indicated that, contrary to the net down-scale transfer of energy found in the unburnt reactants, advective processes lead to a net transfer of energy from small to large scales in the flame brush close to the products. Since this study, we have continued to examine multi-scale turbulence-flame interactions and the spectral structure of turbulence in premixed flames using structure function, differential filtering, and wavelet analyses. Taken together, these studies represent an in-depth and coordinated effort to understand the multi-scale nature of turbulence and premixed flames, and our group has subsequently become one of the leaders in this area of study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To better understand the effects of turbulence on chemical reactions in the flame, we have developed and used a Lagrangian analysis to track changes in chemical species concentrations and thermodynamic variables as they occur in fluid parcels traveling through a premixed flame. We found that temperature and chemical species evolutions along fluid trajectories were non-monotonic due to the effects of molecular transport, that fluid parcel residence times during combustion were substantially shorter as the turbulence intensity increased, and that the turbulent flame speed could be predicted using only Lagrangian information. These results have implications for our understanding of turbulent flame structure, chemical reaction pathways, flame speed predictions, and the formation of reactant pockets in highly turbulent flames. We have now extended this analysis to the study of autoignition and combustion modes in highly compressible reactive turbulence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="turbulence-model-development-using-approximate-bayesian-computation">Turbulence model development using Approximate Bayesian Computation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Real-world turbulent flows are challenging to simulate due to the high computational cost of resolving all their relevant spatial and temporal scales. There are two common approaches to reduce the cost of such simulations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Large_eddy_simulation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Large-Eddy Simulations (LES)&lt;/a>, which directly resolve turbulence on large scales and use subgrid-scale (SGS) models to represent small-scale physics&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reynolds-averaged_Navier%E2%80%93Stokes_equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reynolds averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS)&lt;/a> approaches, which resolve only averaged quantities and model turbulent fluctuations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, there is no universally accurate turbulence model in either of these approaches. Besides that, all models rely on empirical coefficients that we must calibrate for different flows and geometries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We suggest using the
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approximate_Bayesian_computation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC)&lt;/a> methods, also known as likelihood-free methods. ABC is a data-driven approach, which uses experimental or higher fidelity data to approximate the probability distribution of model parameters. As a result, we can choose model parameters and quantify their uncertainty based on (or even sample from) this estimated probability distribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ABC is based on the Bayesian approach but does not require knowing the analytical expression for a likelihood function. The primary advantages of ABC are its lower cost relative to full Bayesian methods and its flexibility in parameter estimation for complex models, e.g., turbulence models, which consist of partial differential equations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We created a framework called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/olgadoronina/ABC_MCMC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TurbABC&lt;/a> for turbulent model parameters estimation. TurbABC combines ABC with Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling, an adaptive proposal, and calibration steps to accelerate the parameter estimation process. We demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of TurbABC by estimating parameters of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonlinear SGS closures using reference data from direct numerical simulations of homogeneous isotropic turbulence&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonequilibrium anisotropy RANS closure in homogeneous turbulent flow with rapidly changing strain tensor&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>RANS model parameters estimation in inhomogeneous turbulent flow (axisymmetric transonic bump)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>