<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RANS | TESLa | CU</title><link>https://teslacu.org/tag/rans/</link><atom:link href="https://teslacu.org/tag/rans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>RANS</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©</copyright><image><url>https://teslacu.org/images/logo_hu6aacdf845f8f280e903ca743076c606a_22838_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>RANS</title><link>https://teslacu.org/tag/rans/</link></image><item><title>Industrial systems</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/industrial_systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/industrial_systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>With Prof. Greg Rieker at CU, we have performed joint experimental and computational research on catalytic and ribbon burners used for industrial processing of polymer films on chilled rollers. On the computational side, we have developed a simulation testbed in OpenFOAM for the study of temperature, flow fields, and heat transfer processes (i.e., radiation and convection) above the burner and in the burner/roller interaction region. The simulation tool has been used to examine a wide range of conditions, including different roller speeds, burner/roller spacings, burner orientations, and power fluxes. Burners operating in isolation and as part of a larger array have also been studied. Simulations have provided 3D temperature, flow, and heat transfer fields for each of these cases, revealing several useful design heuristics, including the advantage of a down-firing burner configuration, the negative impacts of convective heat transfer on temperature uniformity, and the advantageous effects on uniformity of flow-blocking by the roller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Approximate Bayesian computation (ABC) is a data-driven technique that uses many low-cost numerical simulations to estimate unknown physical or model parameters (e.g., boundary conditions and material properties), as well as their uncertainties, given reference data from real-world experiments or higher-fidelity numerical simulations. We have used ABC to estimate unknown parameters in simulations of complex thermal-fluid flows, and the technique has been demonstrated for the estimation of unknown boundary conditions in experiments of high temperature burners used for polymer film flame treatments. These tests show that ABC provides accurate and reasonably certain estimates of inflow parameters even when the model simulations imperfectly represent the physics underlying the reference experimental data. We also demonstrate the use of ABC to estimate unknown model parameters in large eddy simulations and Reynolds averaged Navier-Stokes simulations of turbulent flows. ABC is thus shown to be a versatile technique for estimating unknown physical and model parameters, resulting in substantial improvements in simulation accuracy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turbulent flows</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/turbulence_modeling/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="turbulence-model-development-using-approximate-bayesian-computation">Turbulence model development using Approximate Bayesian Computation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Real-world turbulent flows are challenging to simulate due to the high computational cost of resolving all their relevant spatial and temporal scales. There are two common approaches to reduce the cost of such simulations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Large_eddy_simulation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Large-Eddy Simulations (LES)&lt;/a>, which directly resolve turbulence on large scales and use subgrid-scale (SGS) models to represent small-scale physics&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reynolds-averaged_Navier%E2%80%93Stokes_equations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reynolds averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS)&lt;/a> approaches, which resolve only averaged quantities and model turbulent fluctuations&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, there is no universally accurate turbulence model in either of these approaches. Besides that, all models rely on empirical coefficients that we must calibrate for different flows and geometries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We suggest using the
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approximate_Bayesian_computation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC)&lt;/a> methods, also known as likelihood-free methods. ABC is a data-driven approach, which uses experimental or higher fidelity data to approximate the probability distribution of model parameters. As a result, we can choose model parameters and quantify their uncertainty based on (or even sample from) this estimated probability distribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ABC is based on the Bayesian approach but does not require knowing the analytical expression for a likelihood function. The primary advantages of ABC are its lower cost relative to full Bayesian methods and its flexibility in parameter estimation for complex models, e.g., turbulence models, which consist of partial differential equations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We created a framework called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/olgadoronina/ABC_MCMC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TurbABC&lt;/a> for turbulent model parameters estimation. TurbABC combines ABC with Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling, an adaptive proposal, and calibration steps to accelerate the parameter estimation process. We demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of TurbABC by estimating parameters of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonlinear SGS closures using reference data from direct numerical simulations of homogeneous isotropic turbulence&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>nonequilibrium anisotropy RANS closure in homogeneous turbulent flow with rapidly changing strain tensor&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>RANS model parameters estimation in inhomogeneous turbulent flow (axisymmetric transonic bump)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Wind energy</title><link>https://teslacu.org/project/wind_energy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teslacu.org/project/wind_energy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using adjoint optimization and three-dimensional Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes (RANS) simulations, we developed a new gradient-based approach for optimally siting wind turbines within utility-scale wind plants. By solving the adjoint equations of the flow model, the gradients needed for optimization were found at a cost that was independent of the number of control variables, thereby permitting optimization of large wind plants with many turbine locations. Moreover, compared to the common approach of superimposing prescribed wake deficits onto linearized flow models, the computational efficiency of the adjoint approach allowed the use of higher-fidelity RANS flow models that can capture nonlinear turbulent flow physics within a wind plant. The RANS flow model was implemented in the Python finite element package FEniCS and the derivation of the adjoint equations was automated within the dolfin-adjoint framework. Layout optimization was demonstrated for complex wind roses, including a full annual energy production (AEP) layout optimization over 36 inflow directions and 5 windspeed bins.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>