<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | TESLa@CU</title>
    <link>/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of aerodynamics of a moving body prescribed by immersed boundaries on dynamically adaptative unstructured mesh</title>
      <link>/author/simulation-of-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-prescribed-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptative-unstructured-mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/author/simulation-of-aerodynamics-of-a-moving-body-prescribed-by-immersed-boundaries-on-dynamically-adaptative-unstructured-mesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper is devoted to the development of integrated technology for numerical simulation of aerodynamics of moving bodies prescribed by the immersed boundaries method on unstructured meshes. The dynamic mesh adaptation is used to improve the accuracy. The mesh adaptation method in use is built on the base of nodes-redistribution techniques. Its implementation implies the solution of additional differential equation governing the mesh movement. The method allows to keep a topology of the initial mesh and does not increase significantly the computational costs. The technology is developed for 2D formulations and verified on model problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical study of acoustic radiation dynamics of a Rankine vortex</title>
      <link>/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/author/numerical-study-of-acoustic-radiation-dynamics-of-a-rankine-vortex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper continues investigations of a fundamental problem important for understanding the nature of vortex flows: sound radiation by a perturbed Rankine vortex. Results of numerical simulation are presented for both quadrupole and higher-mode radiations. The structure and dynamics of tonal acoustic radiation generated by a vortex are considered in detail. The transition of a Rankine vortex to a perturbed state under small external perturbation is considered. Calculations are performed using the EBR scheme implemented by NOISEtte software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulation of acoustic waves scattering by isolated vortex structures</title>
      <link>/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/author/numerical-simulation-of-acoustic-waves-scattering-by-isolated-vortex-structures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We consider a linear sound scattering by an isolated vortex as one of the fundamental problems in order to investigate an interaction of the vortex flow and acoustic waves. We present numerical simulation results for a planar wave scattered by a Gaussian-core vortex and a cylindrical point source acoustic wave scattered by a Rankine vortex. For numerical simulation we use the EBR scheme on meshes of different types. We compare results to the benchmark solution and we also compare different approaches to numerical simulation of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
